<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@uijl</title>
    <link>http://uijl.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on @uijl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://uijl.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Top Sources</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/hacker-news-top-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/hacker-news-top-sources/</guid>
      <description>One of the two sites that I visit daily is Hacker News. I saw this tweet by its developer (and the co-founder of Y Combinator) a while back and wondered what the most popular sources are for the top posts on Hacker News. Today marks the anniversary of the second launch, so no better time for this blogpost.
The all-time top posts can be found via a very simple search, an empy query sorted by popularity over all time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When are all short .com domains registered?</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/short-.com-domain-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/short-.com-domain-registrations/</guid>
      <description>Short domain names are worth money. Some of the most popular domain names are two- or three-letter .com domains. In the top 20 of the Alexa top 500 there are three short domains listed: rank 7 (qq.com), rank 15 (jd.com) and rank 17 (vk.com). Or even four if you count rank 3 (fb.com), which is listed as facebook.com.
Inspired by some posts on domain registration dates, such as this one, I decided to inspect the registration date of all two-letter and three-letter .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Joris den Uijl. I graduated as a hydraulic engineer from TU Delft in January &amp;lsquo;18. During my study I got more and more interested in &amp;ldquo;tech&amp;rdquo;. I started reading Hacker News, following ProductHunt and taught myself python programming. After my graduation I worked one year as a quantitave consultant in finance. Luckily I got a call from my former graduation supervisor and was able to join a large marine contractor as a Data Engineer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefit of Scoring Right Before The Break</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/benefit-of-scoring-right-before-the-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/benefit-of-scoring-right-before-the-break/</guid>
      <description>I love watching football but there are several commentators in the Netherlands that have the annoying ability to kick in open doors and present useless facts. Unfortunately Dutch teams are often behind in international matches, so a statement that often returns is &amp;ldquo;If they score now, right before the break, they will start the second half with a morale boost&amp;rdquo;.
Although I understand the logic behind this reasoning, I have never seen data that substantiates it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/goals/</guid>
      <description>Since I am trained as a (hydraulic) engineer I learned to code by myself. To prioritize my time I need a clear list of (prioritized) goals. The goal of publishing this list is similar as this website: Forcing myself to showcase my results and goals. If you have any questions or recommendations, please contact me on twitter.
This will be a &amp;ldquo;living&amp;rdquo; document and I&amp;rsquo;ll update this as I came across something else or finished one of the listed goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/reading/</guid>
      <description>I plan to keep a list of the books I have read since past year.
2019 I am reading the following book:
 Rich Dad, Poor Dad - Robert Kiyosaki. On his podcast the author seems to be very arrogant, I do not know yet if his book will be similar.  I have finished only one book yet:
 The Richest man in Babylon - George Clason. Both this book and Rich Dad, Poor Dad get recommended often if you want to learn more about becom financially independent, but I do not find it that insightfull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/recommendations/</guid>
      <description>I like to keep a list of useful resources on the web.
Who to follow I am no other social media platform than twitter, this is my main source of news (I am still in doubt whether to block the word &amp;ldquo;Trump&amp;rdquo;) and I keep up-to-date with tech related news. On twitter I highly recommend following:
 Ryan Hoover, the founder of Product Hunt and therefore ahead of everyone else when it comes to new start-ups, products or trends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>