<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog posts on @uijl</title>
    <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog posts on @uijl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 16:01:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://uijl.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use a Python virtual environment on WSL</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/python-virtual-environment-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/python-virtual-environment-wsl/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this down because I keep forgetting it. It might be usefull for others who want to set-up virtual environments for Python on WSL as well. The first step we want to do is update and upgrade our subsystem. Open bash and use the command below.
root@host: path# sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; upgrade  Once your system is up-to-date you can install the python-virtual environment.
root@host: path# apt-get install python-virtualenv  Windows Subsystem for Linux comes installed with two python versions installed, before we continue you need to decide which Python distribution you want to use for your virtual environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Top Sources</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/hacker-news-top-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/hacker-news-top-sources/</guid>
      <description>One of the two sites that I visit daily is Hacker News. I saw this tweet by its developer (and the co-founder of Y Combinator) a while back and wondered what the most popular sources are for the top posts on Hacker News. Today marks the anniversary of the second launch, so no better time for this blogpost.
The all-time top posts can be found via a very simple search, an empy query sorted by popularity over all time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When are all short .com domains registered?</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/short-.com-domain-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/short-.com-domain-registrations/</guid>
      <description>Short domain names are worth money. Some of the most popular domain names are two- or three-letter .com domains. In the top 20 of the Alexa top 500 there are three short domains listed: rank 7 (qq.com), rank 15 (jd.com) and rank 17 (vk.com). Or even four if you count rank 3 (fb.com), which is listed as facebook.com.
Inspired by some posts on domain registration dates, such as this one, I decided to inspect the registration date of all two-letter and three-letter .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefit of Scoring Right Before The Break</title>
      <link>http://uijl.github.io/posts/benefit-of-scoring-right-before-the-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uijl.github.io/posts/benefit-of-scoring-right-before-the-break/</guid>
      <description>I love watching football but there are several commentators in the Netherlands that have the annoying ability to kick in open doors and present useless facts. Unfortunately Dutch teams are often behind in international matches, so a statement that often returns is &amp;ldquo;If they score now, right before the break, they will start the second half with a morale boost&amp;rdquo;.
Although I understand the logic behind this reasoning, I have never seen data that substantiates it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>